♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 2=
We meet again.
How ridiculous!
What's so ridiculous?
Others force women into marriage,
but you're forcing a man.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Love is a matter of mutual consent.
How can you make it like a deal?
Do you listen to yourself?
What do you mean?
Erya is the daughter of Wang family.
She's more than good enough
for a demon hunter like him.
The Wang family is surely cunning.
Look how frail Young Master Xu is.
Did your Wang family think
he's weak and easy to bully,
so you tried to force him into this?
Stop spouting nonsense!
This Xu Xian
just beat up four of our servants.
You said he is weak?
You said it yourself, four servants!
That proves you used your power
to force a man into marriage
with vile tactics.
I... Nonsense!
Vile tactics?
Xu Xian, who do you think you are?
Erya took a liking to you.
You should thank your luck.
Right, Erya?
Erya?
Erya!
Erya, what are you doing?
Well, actually,
it's not like
I have to marry Young Master Xu.
I think there are better men out there.
Looks like I don't have that luck.
I have things to do, bye then.
Close the door when you leave.
Xu Xian, you'll regret this.
Erya, let's go.
Come on.
Suzhen.
You insist on dressing like a man,
quite charming.
I just did you a big favor.
You'd better change back.
No, I'm here to help you
pass your love trial smoothly.
Stop it.
I'll go scout.
Wait at the usual spot.
(Shanyao Village)
The village is filled with evil aura.
Father! Mother!
Y-You killed my parents!
White Snake, I'll kill you!
It's you.
Miss, why are you here?
It started raining after you left.
You didn't have an umbrella,
so I followed you.
But then you suddenly seemed possessed,
shouting and screaming,
and even held a blade to my neck.
I was caught in an illusion,
relived my past,
and nearly hurt you.
I'm sorry.
But it's dangerous here.
Please leave, Miss.
Are you worried about me?
I'm worried you...
You might get in my way.
(Fool.)
Please leave, Miss.
People here were bewitched
by an evil demon.
They sacrificed kindness to feed it
in hopes of immortality,
which led to the village
being slaughtered.
Resentment fills this area.
You shouldn't stay here.
(Such minor demons could never harm me.)
Since it's so dangerous here,
shouldn't you walk me back?
Then I have no choice
but to force you out.
Watch out!
(Why is she so strong?)
(Oh no, I overdid it.)
(What should I do?)
Young Master Xu, save me!
Young Master Xu, why are you doing this?
Legend says the foul air of graveyards
can turn into a Rakshasa Bird,
as big as a gray crane,
capable of shapeshifting,
and feeds on human eyes.
The Rakshasa Bird is vicious,
yet it seemed afraid of you.
I have a special constitution.
Ordinary demons
can't come anywhere near me.
So you...
(Oh no, he figured it out.)
The pure yang constitution?
Exactly! You're so sharp,
Young Master Xu.
Let's go then. I'll take you home.
Though I have the pure yang constitution
to ward off evil,
I'm still a poor, homeless woman.
Young Master Xu, if you...
Hey! I haven't finished!
Even though I have some family wealth,
I'm all alone.
I only have Qing to protect me.
My relatives are all vicious,
so the two of us just left
with our fortune.
But far away from home...
Miss,
I'm not someone you can rely on.
(Why is this guy so stubborn?)
(Why does he have my scale?)
It's been ten years.
You've finally appeared.
I will track you down this time.
Who is it?
The enemy
who killed my parents.
(I killed his parents?)
(I see into your mind.)
(You have a missing memory.)
When I was undergoing my tribulation,
I ran into that couple by chance.
They seemed to be approaching me
to do something,
and then I was in unbearable pain,
and lost my memory.
Suzhen,
don't worry.
With your kind heart,
you couldn't have killed those mortals.
Something unexpected must have happened
to cause their tragic deaths.
Goddess told you
to repay Xu Xian's favor,
so he must have been
the one who saved you.
Suzhen,
do you remember what happened
between you and Xu Xian?
I can't remember clearly.
Suzhen, let's just be patient.
Don't rush it.
Xu Xian is such a blockhead.
To make him fall in love,
who knows how long it'll take?
Suzhen, you mentioned that day
that Xu Xian was injured
in Shanyao Village.
Qing, will this really work?
Just go do it.
I'm sure you'll win him over.
Men are all the same.
Qing!
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪